[
    {
        "question": "Ic (<em>gan</em>) #### ut on dægræd þywende oxan to felda — I go out at dawn driving oxen to fields",
        "correctAnswer": "ga",
        "explanation":"Here 'gan' is in the first person singular form 'ga' as the subject is 'ic'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ðu (<em>gan</em>) #### beforan Drihtnes ansyne his wegas gearwian — You go before the face of the Lord to prepare His ways",
        "correctAnswer": "gæst",
        "explanation":"Here 'gan' is in the second person singular form 'gæst' as the subject is 'ðu'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Verys lengtentima ond he (<em>gan</em>) #### to tune on .vii. idus Februarii — Fair is Spring and he goes to town on 7 to the ides of February",
        "correctAnswer": "gæþ|gæð",
        "explanation":"Here 'gan' is in the third person singular form 'gæþ' as the subject is 'he'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "He ða gesceop of ðære eorðan eall nytencynn, and deorcynn, ealle ða ðe on feower fotum (<em>gan</em>) #### — He then created of earth all the race of cattle, and the brute race, all those which go on four feet",
        "correctAnswer": "gaþ|gað",
        "explanation":"Here 'gan' is in the plural form 'gaþ' as the subject is 'ealle ða ðe on feower fotum'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ic (<em>gan</em>) #### ða to Godes ðenunge ond ðaet folc gebletsode ond him Godes gerihtu dyde — I went then to God's ministry and blessed the people, and celebrated God's rights before them",
        "correctAnswer": "eode",
        "explanation":"Here 'gan' is in the past first person singular form 'eode' as the subject is 'ic'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Þa þu gingre wære þu gertest þe ond (<em>gan</em>) #### þær þu woldest — When you were younger, you used to dress yourself and used to walk where you wished",
        "correctAnswer": "eodest",
        "explanation":"Here 'gan' is in the past second person singular form 'eodest' as the subject is 'þu'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "He (<em>gan</em>) #### ofer sæ mid drium fotum ond he gestilde windas mid his hæse — He went over the sea with dry feet, and he stilled the winds by his command",
        "correctAnswer": "eode",
        "explanation":"Here 'gan' is in the past third person singular form 'eode' as the subject is 'he'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hie ða to ðam symle sittan (<em>gan</em>) #### wlance to wingedrince ealle his weagesiðas bealde byrnwiggende — Then they went to sit down to the feast, proud at the wine—drinking, all his woeful companions, bold byrnied warriors",
        "correctAnswer": "eodon",
        "explanation":"Here 'gan' is in the past plural form 'eodon' as the subject is 'hie'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ic (<em>gan</em>) #### on minne bat ond rowe ut on þa ea ond weorpe min nett on þa ea — I go into my boat, row out on the water, and cast my net into the water",
        "correctAnswer": "ga",
        "explanation":"Here 'gan' is in the first person singular form 'ga' as the subject is 'ic'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Þu (<em>gan</em>) #### on þinum breoste and etst þa eorðan eallum dagum þines lifes — You go on your breast and eat the earth all the days of your life",
        "correctAnswer": "gæst",
        "explanation":"Here 'gan' is in the second person singular form 'gæst' as the subject is 'ðu'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Þa feng Æscwine to rice þæs cyn (<em>gan</em>) #### to Cerdice ond heold .ii. gear —  Then Æscwine succeeded to the kingdom, the descent goes back to Cerdic, and held it 2 years",
        "correctAnswer": "gæþ|gæð",
        "explanation":"Here 'gan' is in the third person singular form 'gæþ' as the subject is 'þæs cyn'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ne lifað na se man be hlafe anum ac lifað be ðam wordum ðe (<em>gan</em>) #### of Godes muðe — Man lives not by bread alone, but lives by the words which go from the mouth of God.",
        "correctAnswer": "gaþ|gað",
        "explanation":"Here 'gan' is in the plural form 'gaþ' as the subject is 'ðam wordum'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ic (<em>gan</em>) #### fram ðæm fæder ond com in ðisne middangeord efersonað — I went from the father and came in this world again",
        "correctAnswer": "eode",
        "explanation":"Here 'gan' is in the past first person singular form 'eode' as the subject is 'ic'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Þa cwæð he: la freond hu—mæte (<em>gan</em>) #### ðu in — Then he said, 'Lo! Friend, in what manner went you in?'",
        "correctAnswer": "eodest",
        "explanation":"Here 'gan' is in the past second person singular form 'eodest' as the subject is 'þu'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "He (<em>gan</em>) #### cucu and gesund into his byrgene — He went quick and whole into his grave",
        "correctAnswer": "eode",
        "explanation":"Here 'gan' is in the past second person singular form 'eode' as the subject is 'he'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Þine syll (<em>gan</em>) #### ond ða assan wið hie læswodon; þa færlice comon Sabei ond hie ealle us benamon and ðine yrðlingas ofslogon — Your ploughs went and the asses grazed near; then suddenly Sabaeans came, and they took all of us and killed your plowman",
        "correctAnswer": "eodon",
        "explanation":"Here 'gan' is in the past plural form 'eodon' as the subject is 'Þine syll'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ond ic (<em>don</em>) #### æal swa ge biddaþ — And I will do all as you ask",
        "correctAnswer": "do",
        "explanation":"Here 'don' is in the first person singular form 'do' as the subject is 'ic'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hwæt (<em>don</em>) #### þu gif unclæne fiscas beoþ — What do you do if it is unclean fish?",
        "correctAnswer": "dest",
        "explanation":"Here 'don' is in the second person singular form 'dest' as the subject is 'þu'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Gif esne (<em>don</em>) #### his rade þaes daeges, .vi. se wiþ dryhten gebete oþþe sine hyd — If a servant makes a journey of his own on that day, he shall pay 6 shillings compensation to his lord or undergo the lash",
        "correctAnswer": "deþ|deð",
        "explanation":"Here 'don' is in the third person singular form 'deþ' as the subject is 'esne'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ne winne ge ongen ða ðe eow yfel (<em>don</em>) #### — Strive ye not against those who do you wrong",
        "correctAnswer": "doþ|doð",
        "explanation":"Here 'don' is in the plural form 'doþ' as the subject is 'ða ðe'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "On þisse niht manega þingc ic (<em>don</em>) #### — I did many things on this night",
        "correctAnswer": "dyde",
        "explanation":"Here 'don' is in the past first person singular form 'dyde' as the subject is 'ic'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Þu, cnapa, hwæt (<em>don</em>) #### todæg? — You, boy, what did you do today?",
        "correctAnswer": "dydest",
        "explanation":"Here 'don' is in the past second person singular form 'dydest' as the subject is 'þu'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ða behydde Adam hine ond his wif eac swa (<em>don</em>) #### — Then Adam hid himself and his wife also did so",
        "correctAnswer": "dyde",
        "explanation":"Here 'don' is in the past third person singular form 'dyde' as the subject is 'his wif'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hu ne forealdodon þa gewritu þeah ond losodon þonecan þe hit wære swa some swa þa writeras (<em>don</em>) #### — Would not the writings nevertheless wax old and perish, as often as it was done, just as the writers did",
        "correctAnswer": "dydon",
        "explanation":"Here 'don' is in the plural form 'dydon' as the subject is 'þa writeras'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ic melke hie tweowa on dæg þærto ge cyse ge buteran ic (<em>don</em>) #### ond ic eom getrywe hlaforde minum — I milk them twice a day, then I do the cheese and the butter, and I am faithful to my lord",
        "correctAnswer": "do",
        "explanation":"Here 'don' is in the first person singular form 'do' as the subject is 'ic'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hwæt (<em>don</em>) #### þu be þinre huntunge? — What do you do about your catch?",
        "correctAnswer": "dest",
        "explanation":"Here 'don' is in the second person singular form 'dest' as the subject is 'þu'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ða se hehsta Dema ædre mid elne onbryrde swa he (<em>don</em>) #### anra gehwylcne herbuendra þe hyne him to helpe seceð mid ræde ond mid rihte geleafan — Then the highest judge swiftly inspired her with courage, as He does each person who seeks His help with reason and right belief",
        "correctAnswer": "deþ|deð",
        "explanation":"Here 'don' is in the third person singular form 'deþ' as the subject is 'he'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ðæt cild weox swa swa oðre cild (<em>don</em>) #### — The child grew as other children do",
        "correctAnswer": "doþ|doð",
        "explanation":"Here 'don' is in the plural form 'doþ' as the subject is 'oðre cild'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Cumað ond geseoð ðone man ðe me sæde ealle ða ðing ic (<em>don</em>) #### — Come and see the man who said to me all the things I did",
        "correctAnswer": "dyde",
        "explanation":"Here 'don' is in the past first person singular form 'dyde' as the subject is 'ic'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "God cwæð to ðam wife: Hwi (<em>don</em>) #### ðu ðæt? Heo cwæð: Seo nædre bepæhte me and ic ætt. — God said to the woman, 'why did you do that?' She said, 'the snake deceived me and I ate'",
        "correctAnswer": "dydest",
        "explanation":"Here 'don' is in the past second person singular form 'dydest' as the subject is 'ðu'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Frineð he for þære mænige hwær se man sie se ðe swa he ær on ðam beame (<em>don</em>) #### — He will ask before the multitude where that man may be who wanted to taste a bitter death just as he did on that tree before",
        "correctAnswer": "dyde",
        "explanation":"Here 'don' is in the past third person singular form 'dyde' as the subject is 'he'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Gif we ænige bote gebidan scylan þonne mote we þæs to Gode earnian bet þonne we ær þysan (<em>don</em>) #### — If we shall experience any remedy, then we must deserve that of God better than we have previously done",
        "correctAnswer": "dydon",
        "explanation":"Here 'don' is in the past plural form 'dydon' as the subject is 'we'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    }
]